Guide to the Michael De Lisio and Irving Drutman Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1928-1999; Series II; 5.42; (5 boxes)
  - Hartman, George and Pamela Bianco, 1973, undated (Box 9)
  - Healy, Tim, 1958-1961, undated (Box 9)
  - Hellman, Lillian, 1965-1975 (Box 9)
  - Hill, Jerome, 1957-1961, undated; 2 (Box 9)
  - Hornby, Mary, 1972 July 8 (Box 9)
    Contains photocopy of letter sent to Hornby from Djuna Barnes thanking Hornby for copy of Paris Was Yesterday.
  - Isherwood, Christopher, 1972-1978 (Box 9)
  - Kane, Whitford, undated (Box 9)
  - Katz, Leslie, 1975 (Box 9)
  - Kelly, Betty, 1977-1990 (Box 9)
  - Kelly, Richard, 1937-1944, undated (Box 9)
  - Kemper, Cynthia, 1980s (Box 9)
  - Kent, Charlotte, 1980 October 3; 2 (Box 9)
  - Kirstein, Lincoln, 1941-1946 (Box 9)
  - Knopf, Mildred, 1943 September 7 (Box 9)
  - Koshland, Bill, 1941-1944 (Box 9)
  - Kronenberger, Louis, 1952-1972 (Box 9)
  - Kull, Chris, 1984 March 7 (Box 9)
  - Lane, Frances, 1979 (Box 9)
  - Lange, Ed, 1972, undated (Box 9)
  - La Scala Autographs, 1990 (Box 9)
    Letter from De Lisio proposing sale of letters from Irving Berlin and Ingrid Bergman, with copies of the letters.
  - Lee, Essie, 1980s; 2 (Box 9)
  - Lenya, Lotte, circa 1958-1962; 2 (Box 9)
  - Lieberman, Bill, undated (Box 9)
  - Lillie, Beatrice, 1950 March 4 (Box 9)
  - Loos, Anita, 1950-1955, undated (Box 9)
  - Magnani, Anna, 1942 (Box 9)
  - Magriel, Christine, 1956-1985 (Box 9)
  - Maloney, Dan, 1950-1986, undated; 4 (Box 9)
  - McKinney, Donald, 1979-1980 (Box 9)
  - McPhee, Colin, circa 1950-1956; 2 (Box 9)
  - Mercury Theatre, 1938 Februray 14 (Box 9)
  - Minneapolis Society of Fine Arts, 1971 May 20 (Box 9)
  - Mouser, Debbie, 1994 June 21 (Box 9)
  - Murray, Natalia, 1977-1988, undated (Box 9)
  - Newell, Laura, undated (Box 9)
  - The New Yorker, 1928 December 15 (Box 9)
  - Odets, Clifford, 1950-1952 (Box 9)
  - Orwell, Sonia, circa 1957-1962; 2 (Box 9)
  - Owens, Jeanne, undated (Box 9)
  - Paley, Emily, 1969-1985; 2 (Box 9)
  - Peirce, Alzira, undated (Box 9)
  - Peters, Dewitt, undated (Box 9)
  - Pierce, Waldo, 1937-1941; 2 (Box 9)
  - Pieters, Christine, 1994 (Box 9)
  - Powell, Dawn, 1958-1961, undated (Box 9)
  - Quartaro, Martin, 1986, undated (Box 9)
  - Renault, Francis, undated (Box 9)
  - Roberts, Alan, 1952 June 5 (Box 9)
  - Rorem, Ned, 1985, 1990, undated (Box 9)
    Includes letter to Rorem from De Lisio regarding Drutman's work for Cocteau's "Beauty and the Beast."
  - Ross, Alvin, 1958-1975; 2 (Box 9)
  - Rutenberg, Craig, 1973-1988, undated (Box 9)
  - Santoro, Joe, 1960 (Box 9)
  - Schwartz, Sandy, 1980 (Box 9)
  - Shawn, Bill, 1989 (Box 9)
  - Sherman, Hiram, 1950-1976; 4 (Box 9)
  - Sitwell, Osbert, 1965 May 6 (Box 10)
  - Sortor, David, 1971-1974, undated; 2 (Box 10)
  - Stewart, Lawrence, circa 1970-1988; 2 (Box 10)
  - ---, Suzanne, undated (Box 10)
  - Tellini, Piero, 1952-1969 (Box 10)
  - Trevelyan, Raleigh, 1966-1981, undated; 2 (Box 10)
  - Tynan, Kenneth, 1977 April 7 (Box 10)
  - Valkus, Jimmy, 1980-1989, undated; 2 (Box 10)
  - Vinson, Billy, 1960s-1970s (Box 10)
  - Walling, Christopher, 1977-1988, undated; 2 (Box 10)
  - Waugh, Evelyn, undated (Box 10)
    Photocopy of letter to Drutman from Waugh.
  - Wescott, Glenway, 1951-1952 (Box 10)
  - Whitford, Kane, 1953-1954 (Box 10)
  - Wortzel, Adrianne, 1985-1987, undated (Box 10)
  - Wright, William, 1974-1985, undated (Box 10)
  - Young, Gavin, 1968, undated (Box 10)
  - Zeffirelli, Franco, undated (Box 10)
  - Letters in response to Michael De Lisio's limerick contest for movie "Little Hut", 1957 (Box 11)
    Includes responses from Noel Coward, Ira Gershwin, Marianne Moore, and Ogden Nash.
  - Letters of condolence regarding Irving Drutman's death, 1978; 4 (Box 11)
  - Letters regarding De Lisio's profile in Connoisseur, 1985 (Box 11)
  - Christmas cards, 6 (Box 11)
    Includes cards illustrated by Irving Drutman.
  - Family correspondence, 1950-1980; 6 (Box 11)
    Includes notes regarding family birth and death dates.
  - Unsorted correspondence, 1940s-1980s; 18 (Box 12)
- Personal and Professional Papers, 1941-2002; Series III; 7; (7 boxes)
  Not arranged in any particular order.
  This series contains legal, financial, and medical records, passports, material regarding real estate, and other papers regarding personal matters in addition to professional papers, such as De Lisio's exhibitions, art sales, and letters to the editor.
  - Book reviews -- Miscellaneous authors, 1994-1996, undated (Box 13)
  - Exercises, undated (Box 13)
  - American Society of Composers, Authors and Publishers -- Royalty statements, 1978-1996; 2 (Box 13)
  - Vanguard -- Portfolio statements, 1996-2000; 5 (Box 13)
  - Townley Capital Management, Inc., 1996-2000; 6 (Box 13)
  - Amalia De Lisio -- Funeral arrangements, 1989 (Box 13)
  - Princeton University, Beardsley donation, 1998-1999 (Box 13)
  - Nancy Netzer, 1998-1999, undated (Box 13)
  - McMullen Museum of Art, Boston College -- Exhibition, 1998; 5 (Box 13)
  - Brown, Harris, Stevens, 1996-1998 (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous lists, undated (Box 14)
  - The Lighthouse Catalog, undated (Box 14)
  - Hanover Gallery -- De Lisio / Sculpture, 1969-1970, undated; 2 (Box 14)
  - Queer Nation, 1993-1996, undated (Box 14)
  - Manhattan Shade & Glass Co., Inc., 1996 (Box 14)
  - Modern Art Foundry, 1997 (Box 14)
  - Healing Magnets -- Information, undated (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous newspaper clippings and notes, 1993, undated (Box 14)
  - Joel Meisner & Company, Inc., circa 1974-1991 (Box 14)
  - Bio feedback -- Pain, undated (Box 14)
  - Travel notes & information -- De Lisio, Drutman, 1979-1983, undated (Box 14)
  - Unemployment Insurance -- De Lisio, 1960s (Box 14)
  - Medical advice -- Peter Camilli, Miami, undated (Box 14)
  - Copyright information, 1978 (Box 14)
  - Passports -- De Lisio (Box 14)
  - Provenance -- De Lisio, 1971, undated; 2 (Box 14)
  - Party guest list, 1966-1994, undated (Box 14)
  - Poetry -- General, miscellaneous, undated (Box 14)
  - The Round Table, 1997 (Box 14)
  - Old stamps, undated (Box 14)
  - Social Security -- De Lisio, 1973-1999 (Box 14)
  - Obituaries, circa 1989-1996 (Box 14)
  - Tax files, 1976-1990; 4 (Box 14)
  - Christmas card lists, 1981-1990 (Box 14)
  - Prostate cancer, 1996 July (Box 14)
  - Operation (spinal), 1995 (Box 14)
  - Blue Cross / Blue Shield, 1997-2003; 4 (Box 15)
  - Medicare, 1998-1999; 2 (Box 15)
  - Costa Rica / San Jose, 1980s (Box 15)
  - Chubb Insurance, 1988-2000; 5 (Box 15)
  - Apartment 2 NW, circa 1976-1996; 3 (Box 15)
  - America Online, 1997 (Box 15)
  - New York Times, 1966 March 27 (Box 15)
  - The New Yorker, interview -- Book / De Lisio, 1955, undated (Box 15)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1995-1996 (Box 15)
  - Bohemian Club -- Brent Williams, 1993-1996 (Box 16)
  - AARP, 1997-1998 (Box 16)
  - Appliances, undated; 2 (Box 16)
  - Bank of New York, 2000 (Box 16)
  - AT&T Universal Card, 1998 (Box 16)
  - Beinecke, 1985-1999 (Box 16)
  - Martin Cohen, Attorney at Law, 1996 (Box 16)
  - Harry Ransom Humanities Research Centre, 1999 (Box 16)
  - Charles H. Greenthal, Management, 1998-2000; 2 (Box 16)
  - Brokers, 1999, undated (Box 16)
  - Computer information -- De Lisio, 1997 (Box 16)
  - JoAnne's Bed & Back Shops, 2000 (Box 16)
  - Harcourt, Brace & Company, 1998-2000 (Box 16)
  - Richard Hahn, lawyer, 1999-2000 (Box 16)
  - The New York Times, letters from De Lisio, undated (Box 16)
  - Hirshhorn Museum, 1995-1996 (Box 16)
  - Kaplan, Richard, 1996-1999 (Box 16)
  - Jaffoni, Joe, 1996-1997 (Box 16)
  - Apartment, 1999 (Box 16)
  - Amherst College Library -- John Lancaster, 1999 (Box 16)
  - Smith College, 1980-1998 (Box 16)
  - Lighthouse International, 1999 (Box 16)
  - Guy Berubé, undated (Box 16)
  - Hauswedell & Nolte, 2000-2001 (Box 16)
  - Swann Galleries, 2000 (Box 16)
  - Trauner -- De Lisio lawyer, 1998 (Box 16)
  - Yale University Library Associates, 1999 (Box 16)
  - Ideas for sculptures, 1988-1990, undated (Box 16)
  - Paul Cadmus, 1999 (Box 16)
  - Charles Demuth, "Beach Scene", 1999-2000 (Box 16)
  - David Yurman, 1999 (Box 16)
  - Zabriskie Gallery - De Lisio, 1986 (Box 16)
  - Receipts, 1996-2002; 5 (Box 16)
  - Louise Ross Gallery -- De Lisio / Sculpture, 1994 (Box 16)
  - Metropolitan Museum -- Helen Otis, 1992 October 5 (Box 16)
  - Antonio Souza Gallery, Mexico City -- De Lisio / Sculpture, 1969 (Box 16)
  - Nova Scotia College of Art & Design -- De Lisio / Art, 1970s (Box 16)
  - Guild Hall, Easthampton -- De Lisio / Art, 1994 (Box 16)
  - Paris / Correspondence -- De Lisio / Sculpture, 1973 (Box 16)
  - Caremark (empty folder), undated (Box 16)
  - American Express, 1998 (Box 16)
  - Bell Atlantic, 1998 (Box 16)
  - Bank of New York, 1998 (Box 16)
  - Time-Warner Cable, 1998 (Box 16)
  - Medical, miscellaneous, 1998 (Box 16)
  - Jurgens, Robert, accountant, 1998 (Box 16)
  - Donations, 1996-1998 (Box 16)
  - Con Edison, 1998 (Box 16)
  - Bank of New York, 1998-1999 (Box 17)
  - Donations -- De Lisio, 1999 (Box 17)
  - Mc Warehouse Computer, 1997 (Box 17)
  - Driver's license, past -- De Lisio, circa 1911-1988 (Box 17)
  - Documents -- De Lisio, 1950s-1970s (Box 17)
  - Selective service, 1942-1947 (Box 17)
  - Loeb Rhoades Hornblower, 1977-1979 (Box 17)
  - Sketch pad, undated (Box 17)
  - Note pad, undated (Box 17)
  - Printed contents, laptop, undated (Box 17)
  - Epstein, Joseph, "Max Beerbohm and law of levity", undated (Box 17)
  - Photographs used for sculptures -- De Lisio, undated (Box 17)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1968, undated (Box 17)
  - Toulouse-Lautrec sculpture, undated (Box 17)
  - Publicity -- De Lisio, 1970, undated (Box 17)
  - Canceled checks (photocopies), 2002 (Box 17)
  - Hirshhorn Collection -- De Lisio / Sculpture, 1967-1985 (Box 17)
  - Longbeach Museum -- De Lisio / Sculpture, 1973-1975 (Box 17)
  - Libraries -- De Lisio / Sculpture, 1970s (Box 17)
  - Museum of Modern Art, 1962-1964, undated (Box 17)
  - The Minneapolis Institute of Arts -- De Lisio / Sculpture, 1969-1977 (Box 17)
  - Guggenheim Memorial Foundation-- De Lisio, 1986 (Box 17)
  - Greenwich Library -- De Lisio / Sculpture, 1976 (Box 17)
  - Grants, miscellaneous -- De Lisio / Sculpture, 1975-1986 (Box 17)
  - Galleries, miscellaneous -- De Lisio / Art, 1971-1984, undated (Box 17)
  - Folger Shakespeare Library -- De Lisio / Sculpture, 1985-1986 (Box 17)
  - Princeton University Library -- De Lisio / Sculpture, 1972-1974 (Box 17)
  - College, University, Museums, Art Galleries -- De Lisio / Sculpture, 1970-1981 (Box 17)
  - Brooke Alexander, Inc., 1977-1978 (Box 17)
  - Arts Club of Chicago - De Lisio / Sculpture, 1973-1977 (Box 17)
  - Museums, miscellaneous -- De Lisio / Sculpture, 1971-1987 (Box 17)
  - Wichita Art Museum -- De Lisio / Sculpture, 1972 (Box 17)
  - Sculpture tips -- De Lisio, 1987, undated (Box 18)
  - Cosmopolitan Club -- De Lisio / Sculpture, 1980 (Box 18)
  - Quotations -- De Lisio / Sculpture, undated (Box 18)
  - Santa Barbara Museum of Art -- De Lisio, 1970s (Box 18)
  - Smith College Museum -- De Lisio / Sculpture, 1974-1988 (Box 18)
  - Lists -- De Lisio, 1970-1974, undated (Box 18)
  - De Lisio pending, 2000, undated (Box 18)
  - Expense sheets, 2001-2002 (Box 18)
  - Lutz and Carr, accountant, 1999, undated (Box 18)
  - Accounting expenses, 2000 (Box 18)
  - Con Edison, 2002 (Box 18)
  - Charles H. Greenthal, 2002 (Box 18)
  - Verizon and AT&T, 2002 (Box 18)
  - Chubb + ASCAP, 2002 (Box 18)
  - Miscellaneous receipts, circa 1998-2002; 8 (Box 18)
  - Financial records relating to Fire Island, circa 1965-1990; 19 (Box 19)
  - Family documents -- De Lisio, circa 1941-1990; 2 (Box 19)
  - Sculpture dimensions, undated (Box 19)
  - Actors' Fund, 1984-1985 (Box 19)
- Writings, 1931-1992; Series IV; 5.42; (6 boxes)
  Series IV is organized into two subseries: Michael De Lisio and Irving Drutman.
  This series is comprised of drafts of writings, audiovisual material, correspondence, and royalty statements relating to De Lisio and Drutman's writings. Included are drafts of De Lisio's poetry and unpublished autobiography. Evidence of Irving Drutman's work as a lyricist, journalist, memoirist, and editor can be found in drafts, research notes, and correspondence reflecting his creative process. The series also provides insight into Drutman's work with Janet Flanner to publish her memoirs Paris Was Yesterday and London Was Yesterday and collected writings Janet Flanner's World. The series contains drafts for Drutman's memoir, Good Company and an unpublished sequel, Eccentric Characters, Dubious Company. Drutman's work as a lyricist can also be traced in the series, which contains his work with Jack Lawrence. De Lisio and Drutman's published writing can also be found in the Printed Materials series.
  - Michael De Lisio
    - "Clyde Rule," draft, typescript, non-fiction short story, undated (Box 20)
    - List of plays from the 1920s, undated (Box 20)
    - Autobiography, drafts, typescripts and research notes, 1930s-1990s; 29 folders, 7 8mm videocassettes (Box 20)
      Conditions Governing Access
      Box 20 (videocassettes): Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - "De Lisio/Book" tape 1, page 1-113, 1999-05-25; YCALMSS756_0001; 1; 02:04:38 (Box 20, Item barcode 39002102339786)
    - "De Lisio/Book" tape 2, pages 113-163, undated; YCALMSS756_0002; 1; 01:03:53; This tape had playback problems. (Box 20, Item barcode 39002102339794)
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
      Notes states that "videotape is only good halfway, defective cassette, go to tape #3)
    - "De Lisio/Book" tape 3, pages to 330, undated; YCALMSS756_0003; 1; 00:41:57; The sound cuts out at 00:24:32. This is a "scene change", but there is no audio for the rest of the tape. (Box 20, Item barcode 39002102339810)
      A note with the tape states it could be "defective (but double check)".
    - "De Lisio/Book" tape 4, 00:00 - 34:20 pages 285 to 329; 34:30 - pages 329 to 484, 1999 July 29 and 1999 August 16; YCALMSS756_0004; 1; 01:42:27 (Box 20, Item barcode 39002102339810)
    - Unidentified (1 of 2), undated; YCALMSS756_0005; 1 (Box 20, Item barcode 39002102339828)
    - Unidentified (2 of 2), undated; YCALMSS756_0006; 1; This tape appears to be blank. It has not been digitized. (Box 20, Item barcode 39002102339836)
    - Unsorted poems, undated; 12 (Box 20)
    - Unsorted poems, undated; 4 (Box 21)
    - Unsorted notes, undated; 12 (Box 21)
  - Irving Drutman
    - "Broadway Fifty Years Ago," draft, typescript, and related correspondence, 1973 (Box 22)
    - "Dark Stallion," draft, typescript, undated (Box 22)
    - Eccentric Characters, Dubious Company, drafts, typescripts, corrected, 1981, undated; 10 (Box 22)
      Unpublished autobiography written as a sequel to Good Company: A Memoir, Mostly Theatrical.
    - Good Company: A Memoir, Mostly Theatrical, drafts, typescripts, corrected, 1970s; 9 (Box 22)
    - Good Company: A Memoir, Mostly Theatrical, drafts, typescripts, corrected, 1975-1981, undated; 10 (Box 23)
    - "A Good Murder," draft, typescript, and research notes, undated; 2 (Box 23)
    - Janet Flanner's World, drafts, typescript and research notes, 1971-1992, undated; 8 (Box 23)
    - Janet Flanner's World, drafts, typescript and research notes, 1973-1991, undated; 3 (Box 24)
    - London Was Yesterday, drafts, typescript, research notes, correspondence, and royalty statements, 1970s; 3 (Box 24)
    - "Much Ado About Nothing" by Edwin Justus, Kurt Weill, Ira Gershwin, undated (Box 24)
    - "Murieliste," draft, typescript, undated (Box 24)
    - Paris Was Yesterday, draft, typescript, correspondence, royalty statements, 1980s; 12 (Box 24)
    - "Vile Bodies," draft, typescript, first act of play adapted from Evelyn Waugh novel, 1931 (Box 24)
    - Book ideas, undated; 3 (Box 24)
    - Lyrics for F.I. Musicals, drafts, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 25)
    - Lyrics, autograph manuscript, typescripts, corrected, printed versions, and newspaper clippings, 1945-1946; 3 (Box 25)
      Includes "Sunday Morning," "I'm Advertising for a Baby," "She Gave Up Love for Everything (Money, Money, Money)," "The Girl with the Mustache," "Do You or Don't You," "Come to the Circus," "Opening," "Mama Never Told Me," Suddenly It's Spring," "The World I Live In," "Don't Blame Me for Everything," "Tell Me No Stories," "Lullaby for Rain," "What Do You Care?," "My Future's a Thing of the Past," "Schmoos," "What the Hell," "The Cream in My Coffee," "Sunday Afternoon," "And So They Were Married," "The Naughty Naughty Nineties," "Be Red for the Red White and Blue," "The Twilight Song," and untitled. Includes lyrics written with Jack Lawrence.
    - Poems, autograph manuscript, undated (Box 25)
    - Article on Tallulah Bankhead, drafts, typescript (Box 25)
    - Articles written for Cosmopolitan Magazine on Edna Ferber, Oscar Levant, and Lincoln Kirstein, and related correspondence, 1937-1940 (Box 25)
    - Articles, drafts, typescript, on Enid Bagnold, Peter Brook, Katherine Cornell, Noel Coward, George Kelly, Ethel Merman, "A Penny Earned," and "Tricks of the Trade," and related correspondence (Box 25)
- Other Papers, 1924-1998; Series V; 4.67; (5 boxes)
  This series contains legal and financial records, address books, scrapbooks, clippings, and other ephemera primarily relating to Irving Drutman. Drutman's career as a lyricist and publicist is documented in contracts, royalties, a list of films in which Drutman was involved, a phonodisc, and scrapbooks with clippings of various movies and plays. The series also provides insight into Drutman's work with performers such as Lotte Lenya and a notebook with anecdotes about his encounters with writers and artists, such as Janet Flanner and Virgil Thomson. The series also includes material relating to Drutman's death, including obituaries, a will, and a copy of his death certificate.
  - Miscellaneous receipts, 1997-1998; 4 (Box 26)
  - Caremark, 1997 (Box 26)
  - Tax receipt, 1996 (Box 26)
  - NYNEX, 1997 (Box 26)
  - Tax figures, 1996-1995; 2 (Box 26)
  - Gottlieb, Adam -- Accountant, undated (Box 26)
  - American Express credit card, 1997 (Box 26)
  - Brown, Harris & Stevens, 1997 (Box 26)
  - Mastercard, 1997 (Box 26)
  - Con Edison, 1997 (Box 26)
  - Chubb, 1997 (Box 26)
  - Time-Warner Cable, 1997 (Box 26)
  - Appointment calendar, 1997 (Box 26)
  - Notebooks (Irving Drutman), 1935-1973; 2 (Box 26)
    Includes notebook "Notes made since 1935 in a cream-colored book, 'The Scribble-In Book' trade mark, which I bought at Woolworth's and on the spine of which I printed 'Anecdotes'."
  - Drutman's graduation book, 1924 (Box 26)
  - Address books, undated; 3 (Box 26)
  - Estimates and drawings for window treatment, undated (Box 27)
  - Harcourt Brace Jovanovich catalogue, 1979 Fall (Box 27)
  - Correspondence, ephemera, and notes relating to campaign to nominate George Gershwin to the Hall of Fame for Great Americans, 1965 (Box 27)
  - Contracts, royalties, and other ephemera relating to Irving Drutman's work as a lyricist and writer, 1946-1997; 5 (Box 27)
    Includes correspondence with the American Society of Composers, Authors & Publishers
  - Clipping regarding "The Private Affairs of Bel-Ami", undated (Box 27)
  - Photograph from Casals Festival, 1957 (Box 27)
  - Drutman's paintings, undated (Box 27)
  - Notes, miscellaneous, undated (Box 27)
  - List of movies Drutman worked on, undated (Box 27)
  - Program for "Time Our for Fun", 1940 (Box 27)
  - Clippings by and about Irving Drutman, 1950-1975; 5 (Box 27)
  - Notes on home decor, 1960s (Box 27)
  - Program for The American Academy of Arts and Letters and the National Institute of Arts and Letters, with autograph notes relating to Bill Christopher, 1969 May 21 (Box 27)
  - Irving Drutman's will, death certificate, and other legal papers, 1977-1990 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence, notes with friends' addresses, hotel and restaurant addresses, passport, and ephemera relating to Irving Drutman's travels, 1960s; 2 (Box 27)
  - Obituary for Irving Drutman, undated (Box 27)
  - Photograph of Irving Drutman and Virgil Thomson by Maurice Grosser, 1976 January (Box 27)
  - Legal documents, including copy of Irving Drutman's birth certificate, 1965-1977; 2 (Box 27)
  - Lists of artists, writers, intellectuals, etc. "Name Game", undated (Box 27)
  - Material relating to Lotte Lenya, including correspondence, copy of will, photographs, clippings, and other ephemera, 1980s; 2 (Box 27)
  - Clippings, correspondence, and other ephemera regarding Virgil Thomson -- Maurice Grosser -- Colin McPhee, 1984-1993 (Box 27)
  - Scrapbook with clippings collected by Irving Drutman, 1927-1931; 2 (Box 28)
  - Scrapbook with photographs and clippings relating to theatre, art, and literature collected by Irving Drutman, 1950s (Box 28)
  - Scrapbook with clippings collected by Irving Drutman, 1927-1946 (Box 29)
  - Scrapbooks with clippings by and about Irving Drutman, 1943-1956; 3 (Box 30)
  - Phonodisc with recording of Mae West singing "Page 54" and "My Man Friday", undated; 1 10" 78 RPM phonodisc (Box 31 (Record Album Storage))
- Photographs, 1890-1990; Series VI; 2; (2 boxes)
  This series is comprised of photographs of Michael De Lisio, Irving Drutman, and their families dating from the 1890s to the 1990s. Photographs of De Lisio and Drutman range from formal portraits to snapshots of vacations abroad and at their property on Fire Island, Long Island. Photographs of De Lisio's artwork and exhibitions can be found in the series, including a proposed statue of Henry James for Washington Square Park in New York City. The series also contains signed portraits of celebrities.
  - Drutman and De Lisio in Cassis, photographed by Jerome Hill, 1957 (Box 32)
  - Michael De Lisio's Navy Pictures, 1943-1944 (Box 32)
  - De Lisio Family, circa 1890-1970s; 10 (Box 32)
  - Drutman Family, 1940s-1970s; 2 (Box 32)
  - Fire Island, 1990s; 7 (Box 32)
  - De Lisio portraits, undated (Box 32)
  - Drutman portraits, undated (Box 32)
  - Greta Garbo, 1983 (Box 32)
  - Michael De Lisio and Irving Drutman, 1930-1958 (Box 32)
  - Irving Drutman and Benny Baker, 1944 January (Box 32)
  - Enrico Ferorelli's photographs for Martha Saxton's piece on Michael De Lisio in Sept 1985 issue of Connoisseur Magazine (Box 32)
  - Photographs relating to proposed Henry James sculpture in Washington Square, undated; 2 (Box 33)
  - Photographs of De Lisio's sculptures, undated; 3 (Box 33)
  - De Lisio (including portrait by William Wright), 1979, undated (Box 33)
  - Negatives, 1946-1953 (Box 33)
    Includes Louis Trabulsi's apartment, Fire Island, Oliver Smith, Bernie Winebaum, Alan Roberts, and Lillian Bassman.
  - Fire Island, early years, book material, 3 (Box 33)
  - Various photographs of friends, 1930-1960; 5 (Box 33)
  - "Good Company", 1942-1950 (Box 33)
  - De Lisio and Drutman portraits by William Wright, 1976 January (Box 33)
  - Opening of exhibition of Drutman's work, undated (Box 33)
  - De Lisio, undated (Box 33)
  - Photographic reproductions of artwork, including portraits of Janet Flanner by Alajalov, Colette by Daniel Malovey, Picasso by De Lisio, and others, undated; 2 (Box 33)
  - Adam's Magic Cropper, undated (Box 33)
  - Framed photograph of Drutman, De Lisio, and others on a beach, 1950s (Box 34 (Art))
- Printed Material, 1927-1995; Series VII; 2.46; (5 boxes)
  This series contains printed material by and about De Lisio and Drutman. These include early poetry published by De Lisio in The New Yorker and later articles about his work as a sculptor, including a piece in Connoisseur and exhibition catalogues. Children's stories written by Drutman for the Works Progress Administration can also be found in this series.
  - The New Yorker, 1927-1934; 6 (Box 35)
  - The New Yorker, 1944-1995; 4 (Box 36)